Guide to the Gerald Robert Vizenor Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- September 2015 Acquisition, 1974-2015; 9.92; (14 boxes) + 2 broadside
  - Lectures on Atomic Bomb, Hiroshima, etc., circa 2011 (Box 92)
  - Email correspondence, 2012-; 3 folders (Box 92)
    Includes material for American Studies course
  - Final report - forming the Native American Studies Association, 1980- (Box 93)
  - Narratives of Genocide, Fall 2008 (Box 93)
  - Treaty Shirts October 2034: A Familiar Treatise on the White Earth Nation, 2015- (Box 93)
  - Empire Treasons book summary and proposal, circa 2014 (Box 93)
  - New England lectures, 2014- (Box 93)
  - London and Vienna lectures, 2014- (Box 93)
  - Treaty Shirts - annotated typescript, circa 2014 (Box 93)
  - Treaty Shirts October 2034, 2015- (Box 93)
  - Photo album - Gerald Vizenor and Laura Hall, circa 2014 (Box 93)
  - Email correspondence, 2012-; 2 folders (Box 93)
  - Blue Ravens, circa 2013; 2 folders (Box 93)
  - Deceit of Peace, circa 2013 (Box 93)
  - Captain Shammer, 2012- (Box 93)
  - Irony Dogs, 2012- (Box 93)
  - Native Stories: An Introduction, 2012- (Box 93)
  - Metaphors of Native Identities, circa 2012 (Box 93)
  - Genocidal Tribunals: Native Rights and Narrative Survivance, circa 2010 (Box 93)
  - Chancers, notes for Breakfast Group seminar discussion, 2005- (Box 93)
  - Natural Estates, circa 2008 (Box 93)
  - "My Life Has Been Full of Chance" An interview with Gerald Vizenor by Anna Jandrey, 2012 October 24 (Box 93)
  - Photographs of Native American art and clothing, circa 2010 (Box 93)
  - Teaching the Postmodern, by Brenda Marshall, circa 1991 (Box 93)
  - A Name, a Face and a Rape: Iowa Victim Tells Her Story, by David Margolick, 1990 March 25 (Box 93)
  - On Evil, by Adam Moore, 2004- (Box 93)
  - Chippewa Constitution, Berkeley notes, 2012- (Box 93)
  - The Ethics of Memory, by Avishai Margalit, 2002- (Box 93)
  - Chateau Thierry, circa 2014 (Box 93)
  - The Constitution of the White Earth Nation promotional material, 2012- (Box 93)
  - Notes on various WWI-related stories; war casualties, etc., circa 2011 (Box 93)
  - The White Earth Nation, 2012- (Box 94)
  - Chair of Tears, 2010- (Box 94)
  - Literature, Theory, and Common Sense, 2004- (Box 94)
  - Course materials for The Atomic Bomb: Los Alamos to Hiroshima, 1995-2012 (Box 94)
    Includes notes, student records, newspaper photocopies, etc.
  - Course Materials for T: Narrative of Atrocity & Genocide, 2005-2012 (Box 94)
  - Atomic Bomb: Los Alamos to Hiroshima, lecture material, circa 1995 (Box 94)
  - Blue Ravens, notes, circa 2012 (Box 94)
  - Blue Ravens, notes and correspondence, 2012- (Box 94)
  - Sakahan essay, 2012- (Box 94)
  - Lecture material by various authors, 1974-2004 (Box 94)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 2010-2012 (Box 94)
    Includes Gerald Vizenor's essays in reprints from two University of Heidelberg journals, a 'the Uptowner' magazine, email correspondence, etc.
  - Holograph notes on HD, imagist poetry, etc, circa 2013-2014 (Box 94)
  - Favor of Crows and Blue Ravens, promotional materials, circa 2014 (Box 94)
  - Japan lectures, 2014- (Box 94)
  - Lectures and essays, 2003-2015 (Box 94)
    Includes Literary Transmotion, Native Cosmototemic Art, Sakahan Symposium, and The Aesthetics of Survivance.
  - WWI research notes, 1985-2013 (Box 94)
  - New England lectures, 2014- (Box 94)
  - Lectures - Kansas City, Minneapolis, White Earth Nation, 2014- (Box 94)
  - Sections of Blue Ravens, circa 2014 (Box 94)
  - Blue Ravens, uncorrected page proofs, circa 2014 (Box 94)
  - The Constitution of the White Earth Nation, 2014-2015 (Box 94)
  - Treaty Shirts October 2034, notes, 2014- (Box 94)
  - Treaty Shirts, Drafts, 2014-2015; 2 folders (Box 94)
  - Treaty Shirts, research materials, 2013-2014 (Box 94)
  - Treaty Shirts, 2014- (Box 94)
  - Treaty Shirts, archive first chapter, 2014- (Box 94)
  - Treaty Shirts October 2034, notes, 2014-; 2 folders (Box 95)
  - Lectures - Kansas City, Minneapolis, White Earth Nation, 2014- (Box 95)
  - Email correspondence, 2014-2015; 4 folders (Box 95)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 2015- (Box 95)
  - John Russel - Bancroft - Vizenor MSS collection, 2010-2011 (Box 95)
    Including email correspondence, photocopy of receipts, and checks.
  - Moby-Dick & Transmotion - Melville Society of Japan, 2014- (Box 95)
  - John Berryman correspondence, 2014- (Box 95)
  - Radcliffe Institute event calendar, 2014- (Box 95)
  - October lecture material, 2014-; 2 folders (Box 95)
  - Haiku, 2014- (Box 95)
  - Heart Creek/Sand Creek haiku, circa 2014 (Box 95)
  - Anishinaabeg Today, 2014 July 02 (Box 95)
  - Texas interview, 2013- (Box 95)
  - Dartmouth College promotional material, 2014- (Box 95)
  - Water Striders: Haiku Poems, circa 1989 (Box 95)
  - Articles about Gerald Vizenor, 1994-2015 (Box 95)
    Includes 'The Chronicle of Higher Education' and 'Konch Magazine' articles.
  - Calm in the Storm: Accalmie, haiku in French, 2014-2015 (Box 95)
  - Calm in the Storm: Accalmie, proof layout, circa 2014 (Box 95)
  - Buddha Visits a Neighborhood Farmers' Market, by Frank Pommersheim, 2014- (Box 95)
  - Anishinaabeg Today, 2015 January 07 (Box 95)
  - Author bios for LaPlaya Author Fest, 2015- (Box 95)
  - Favor of Crows, translation, publications, and correspondence, 2013-2015 (Box 95)
  - Institute of American Indian Arts, 2014-2014 (Box 95)
  - Anishinaabeg Today, 2014 December 03 (Box 95)
  - Florida Atlantic University, Boca Raton, 2014- (Box 95)
  - Reimagining the Munificence of an Ass, from The Holy Land in Transit, 2006- (Box 95)
  - Le Monde, 2014- (Box 95)
  - White Earth Nation, Sovereignty Day, 2014- (Box 95)
  - Kansas City, 2014- (Box 95)
  - Coyote (German magazine), Autumn 2014 (Box 95)
  - Conference photographs, circa 1980 (Box 95)
  - Transmotion, Kent University lecture material, 2014- (Box 95)
  - License plate - New Mexico Tricentennial Commemoration, circa 1980 (Box 95)
  - License plate - Santa Fe Indian School, circa 1980 (Box 95)
  - Constitutional Reform Workbook, 2013- (Box 95)
  - Vizenor in Vienna, PowerPoint presentation, undated (Box 101)
  - Posters, circa 2014 (Box 96)
    Includes the published portrait, "Waa-Na-Taa," or the "Foremost in Battle", a poster celebrating Gerald Vizenor at University of Vienna, and a TILTS poster.
  - Posters, 2011-2014 (Box 97)
    Posters of Sakahan exhibit, poetry reading at University of Arizona, Gerald Vizenor at Wesleyan University, and others.
  - Interior Landscapes and Portrait cover, circa 1990 (Box 98)
  - University of Nebraska Press, poster celebrating Vizenor's Lifetime Achievement Award, 2005-; 1 (Box 99 (Broadside))
  - Gerald Vizenor's surprise birthday party, poster, circa 1993; 1 (Box 100 (Broadside))
  - Electronic media, 2011-2014; 2 (Box 101)